If there's one thing
that separates winners and losers,
it's one thing, marketing.
If you want the hot wife
or the fast car or the nice big house,
you need to get good at marketing.
Without it,
your personal brand will die and
will never reach its full potential.
If I had to come up with a definition of
what marketing is, it'd be this.
Marketing is everything
that you do to attract and retain people.
And although this sounds cheesy
and quite bro-ish, without marketing,
you won't get
paid, and you're not going to get laid.
I am not an expert in business.
I'm not even a guru or really even
that smart.
I'm just good at one thing, and that
is sending traffic.
That's all I do for a job.
I send traffic to websites.
The point of this video,
send traffic to a website.
The point of every single email marketing
campaign I've ever done, to send traffic
to a website. I'm not an influencer.
I just send people to websites.
And the sooner you can appreciate to be
a fantastic digital marketer,
that's all you need to do,
the easier you can start
to get better at it. In this video,
we're going to look at digital versus
traditional marketing,
strategy versus tactics,
the four pillars of
marketing mediums,
organic marketing versus paid marketing,
awareness
versus sales, search versus discovery,
products versus
services, and then B2B versus B2C.
And although they seem like complex
jargon, boring terminologies,
in the next few
minutes or so,
you're going to be able to understand
where you need to put your
attention and where you need to avoid
wasting it.
Marketing is now split into two places,
digital and traditional.
Traditional is TV, radio, print,
and we're going to put face-to-face in
there as
well.
That could be walking the floor as a
personal trainer, it could be networking
in some kind of business sense,
or even cold outreach.
If you were to open a jujitsu gym,
you could knock on the doors of the local
1,000
houses and maybe build your business
that way.
That would go under traditional media.
Although I've got some experience in
face-to-face from running a personal
training
business and working in door-to-door
sales, the real place
that I'm a black belt is
digital marketing. Social media, email,
pay per click, which could be ads, and
landing pages.
We're going to call them LPs for today.
I think the important things to realize
is that although TV and radio do not have
the pulling power that they once did,
maybe 10, 15 years ago,
I still believe that
print and face-to-face traditional
marketing are still powerful tools.
Whether you're a physio, strength
and conditioning coach, personal trainer,
or even
an accountant or an insurance broker,
there is still an element of face-to-face
marketing that you could do going into
local businesses, running free workshops.
And then when it comes to print,
I still think flyering is very much alive.
I even had an idea this morning from my
friend who I train jujitsu with.
He's looking to get new members into his
gym.
I said to him,
"Why not partner with your local coffee
shop that you go to, and
tomorrow morning between 6:00
and 8:00 a.m.
pay for everyone's coffee?" This might
cost you a few hundred dollars, sure.
As every single person goes to pay,
the barista or the owner of the coffee
shop is
to say,
"This coffee has been bought by Evolve Gym
and Thrill.
All they ask is that you take this flyer
in return and consider doing a seven-day
free trial." This leans into what I would
call the law of reciprocity.
Giving someone a flyer in a coffee shop
could feel a bit jarring, a little bit,
"Uh, no, thanks."
But going out of your way, even
if someone doesn't take you up on
the seven-day free trial to buy someone a
coffee, I just know that type of tactic
would win me over. If I
was buying a coffee tomorrow morning
and I went to get an
almond croissant and they said, "Oh,
James, this has been paid for by a massage
parlor down the road. All they ask is
that you take this leaflet
and maybe consider
using them," I don't think I'd be able to
relax until I'd at least booked in for
one massage and go in
and say thanks for the free croissant.
The world that we live in now,
we must appreciate
that digital marketing is
probably going to give us the best return
for investment.
And it doesn't matter how old you are
or how late you are to the game,
the beauty
of digital marketing
is the compounding effect of effort.
Whether this is your email list
or whether this is your social media,
whether this
is your income, this
is the reality of what it looks like to
put your heart and
soul into digital marketing.
Because for the first couple of years,
you're just
getting your reps in,
what it's like to write an email,
what it's like to film
content. By year three,
things start to stick a little bit more.
By year four,
it feels like an automated process
that you couldn't do the day
without, and by day five,
everyone will call you an overnight
success.
Some people do this in two months.
Some people do it in six months.
But it's just really important
that you appreciate,
similar to the compounding
interest that you earn in an interest
savings account, in the area
that most people
give up,
you just need to appreciate it's where the
least will happen.
And it's the area
that 90% of people don't get to,
where you start to see the
amazing returns from it.
The next two things to look at
are strategy and tactics.
When we look at strategy,
we want to look at the model of the
business.
Is it online? Is it in person?
Is it a service? Is it a product?
We want to look at the market.
We don't want to overly niche.
We don't just want to work with 23 to
27-year-old men from Northumbria that are
left-handed,
but we do want to appreciate who our
market is.
What problems do they face?
What solutions could we give them?
How could they relate to our own personal
story? Then we want to think about sales.
Are we going to be making our sales
actively or passively?
If you're someone
that uses sales calls within your
business, that is active.
If you do not turn up on sales calls
and close people, you do not get sales.
But everyone by now really knows
that I prefer passive sales.
What this means is that there
are automations and flows
that people can join into
and jump into.
They can work their way through them,
and you wake up in the morning
with money in your Stripe account.
And then the last point would be media.
What platforms are we going to use?
Are we going to double up on LinkedIn,
or are we going to use YouTube?
These are all components of strategy.
When we look at tactics,
posting frequency.
And again,
the majority of you should be posting
every day.
And for some of you,
that really stresses you out,
but I didn't say you had to
produce an artwork piece of content every
day. A screenshot of a tweet, a carousel.
A carousel post, all you need
is 10 photos and maybe 10 minutes to write
some
captions on it.
If you're telling me you don't have time
to do one post a day,
there is something not just wrong with
your business, but your life.
Content type.
Are you going to go long format like this
where you can accrue hours of sit time?
Are you going to go for short-form content
like TikTok or Instagram?
Timing, how long is
that piece of content going to be?
Is it going to be short, impactful, long?
Packaging,
which can be incredibly important,
especially if you're putting it on
YouTube. And then, of course,
what does the funnel look like?
Right now,
you are inside my digital marketing
funnel.
One of my videos will come up on your
explore feed, and you'll click on it, and
you'll watch it.
Each video in the description has several
call to actions.
For instance,
this week I decided to make a document
that explains to people how to
perfectly create a landing page to get
more conversions and sales.
I give people a link in the description,
there'll be one in this video, where they
can download that asset,
and I'll send it across to them via email.
If they're not interested in landing
pages,
there's also 30 bits of business advice
over 30 days. Then the third link
that I'll put in there
is a link just straight to
the business membership where you see what
it is, what you get, how much it costs,
why to trust me, et cetera. Now,
the landing page template gives you a PDF.
Then over the next 11 days afterwards,
I check in with you and give you a bit of
advice to make sure
that your landing page can convert better.
The 30-day autoresponder hits you for 30
days with businessThis advice that you can
implement into your business on that day.
And then the third one is
if you visit the website,
we have something called a
tracking pixel, which means that from
that point, we can then allocate paid
advertising into people
that have visited that landing page
and potentially not
bought.
We can follow you around with ads
and different offers for other courses,
because if you don't buy the business
mentorship, which is two
and a half thousand
dollars,
maybe the $99 content mastery course
is perfect for you.
No matter which lead magnet you come in
through, we're going to add you to a
database which you can broadcast to,
and if at any point you're not interested,
you
can unsubscribe.
The reason we call it a funnel is this.
At the first point of the funnel
is something called impressions.
That is how many people see my thumbnail
and video.
I know that about 6.2% of all people
that see my videos end up clicking
through and watching. See
that from YouTube analytics.
And then at the moment,
use Ed Lawrence's rev track to see how
many people are
clicking from a video. And we know
that about between 0.3 to 2.7% of
people that watch a video end up clicking.
The reason that the funnel
is an inverted pyramid is
that out of the millions of
people on YouTube,
only several thousand of them
are going to watch.
Out of the several thousand that watch,
only a small percentage of those are going
to click. Out of the people that click,
only a certain percentage of people are
going to finish the emails,
and out of the people
that read the emails, only a
certain amount of people are going to buy.
Now through perfecting and learning
and curating my marketing
approach,
this funnel can become narrower where more
people that start at the top
end up being clients. But for me,
I know all I need to do,
make more content,
get more people watching,
which can mean more clicks, which
is going to mean more
emails, which can mean more sales.
Someone was complaining the other day
that my business mentorship has gone up
33%
in four months. And I said to him, "Mate,
I've been telling you this for ages."
Because the premise of digital marketing
is the bigger my social media following
gets, the more people watch content,
which means more people click, more people
read emails, more people buy it.
And like you saw before,
we're still very much in
the infancy of this channel.
When this channel gets to 300,000
subscribers, that's
going to mean we can tenfold every single
number that goes through this funnel.
And I'm not going to be able to manage 10
times the amount of clients, so the only
lever that I have to manage with demand
for my business is going to be increasing
the prices. Now, talking of my businesses,
we're going to get into the four
pillars. The first one
is going to be the model.
So the offer for Nootonic
is to boost people's productivity with
evidence-based nootropics, which
are kind of supplements for the brain.
We have premium pricing for the product
because we have to source about nine
different ingredients to get in there.
Plus, we also need to build
and grow the business.
We need to have enough margin
that we can build more products to ship
into more
countries to be in more territories.
The delivery of the product
is done through partners like Amazon,
TikTok shop, and
we also ship direct to people.
We're now currently trying to prioritize
direct to
customer because that means
that we can get the contact information of
the
customers so that 12 days after they've
bought a 12-pack,
we can email them saying,
"If you've run out of Nootonic,
feel free to top up." And the reason
that we love
the productivity market so much is that
if today I eat like shit, I'll be fine.
Today, if I don't train, I'll be fine.
Today, if I don't get that much sleep,
I'll be fine.
But today,
if I do not get all the work done
that I need to get done, I am a grumpy
piece of shit.
I see productivity as being like the new
fitness.
The next model,
let's think about the mentorship.
So we're closing in on $3 million worth of
business.
We're not even halfway into our second
year.
Pricing is $2,500 for a lifetime
membership.
We also have satellite courses at $99 to
help people with short-form content.
The reason there's such a price
discrepancy is if you get a satellite
course like
short form content mastery,
there's none of my time, energy,
or effort.
However, the reason that it's two
and a half thousand dollars is this
is lifetime,
and people get access to me in the
Discord.
This is still very cheap considering you
actually get access to me.
I haven't got any coaches at the time of
this video that support me at all.
So every content critique,
every single landing page,
every single website, that is
me.
Some people think it's quite stupid to do
lifetime, but the reason being is
everyone in the community respects not
only each other's time, but my time too.
They don't post content critiques every
single day.
They'll do one or two a week,
and they'll do it when they need it,
and they'll do
it when they're changing up their content
strategy.
And the delivery of it is
that the moment you join,
you get access to me.
But all I ask is
that you watch the modules
that I've made about email marketing,
landing page design, content creation,
so that when you present questions to me
in
the mentorship, two things. One,
I can help you with them, and two,
if I recognize
there's a pattern
and a trend of things that
are all the same, I'll then build out
new things into the course. For instance,
if everyone was asking about ChatGPT, I
would wake up and go,
"To stop me repeating myself,
I'm going to create a whole new
course on ChatGPT." Then we look at the
model for my training app.
You can see we're coming up to $16
million.
This is Australian,
so just through Stripe alone,
that's over 10 million US
dollars.
And probably the most impressive thing
here is the fact that
121,000 customers.
The reason I even show you that
is the majority of
gurus that sit here made all of their
money from teaching people how to make
money.
I've made four times as much money from
running a fitness business than I have
from
being a course bro.
Our offer for affordable online coaching.
As far as the model
that we have for affordable online
coaching, we have a
program-only membership, which
is 16 US dollars per month,
and then our premium
package is 224 US dollars,
but you get four months with that.
So we run a challenge model around the
premium membership, and
if people just want
their program rotated,
16 bucks a month So they're the models to
the business.
Where we have Nutonic,
we have the mentorship,
and we have affordable online
coaching, we have the market, the message,
and the media.
These are the other three pillars.
Now, the target customer between these
is actually quite close in some
respects, because the people
that like Nutonic
are going to be people that value
productivity. People in the mentorship
are probably going to be entrepreneurs.
So we could argue
that the right cohort for the mentorship
would love Nutonic, and
Nutonic would love the mentorship.
As far as affordable online coaching,
it's probably going to be some of my older
audience from me being a personal trainer
and calling people twats on the internet.
So the perfect market for that
is ultimately someone
that just wants their program
written for them and doesn't want to pay
hundreds of dollars for that to happen.
Let me talk about the message we want to
communicate about pain points.
For Nutonic,
that's going to be based around focus,
because if you can't focus,
lock in. The majority of us watching this,
we have maybe one to three hours a day
that we can really dial in
and get work done.
And for a lot of us,
it's just about making the most of that.
The messaging for the mentorship
is a lot of people know
if they could make better
content,
get into a routine of posting frequency,
and understand email
marketing and how to create a landing
page, that they could build an audience of
people that want to buy the stuff they
have.
The problem with most people even watching
this video is you have the skills,
but you do not have the customers.
And it is connecting your skills with the
customers that gives you the business.
We'll make the message there,
make money online.
And then the messaging for AOC
is great and affordable coaching,
because the
reality is coaching shouldn't be
expensive.
Now,
when it comes to the media for the
majority of these, Nutonic is going to be
Instagram and pay-per-click. To grow
and scale the business,
we're going to need to
invest heavily into paid ads.
When we look at the mentorship,
it's YouTube,
Instagram, and pay-per-click.
YouTube in priority to Instagram.
We just end up putting clips on Instagram.
And the pay-per-the-click
is going to be the ads.
The key component
that differentiates this
is Nutonic does not have
a YouTube channel because we don't really
have the audience.
If people are struggling with focus,
they don't go onto YouTube.
But when people are struggling with making
money online, they do.
So this is where the pillar starts to
change a little bit.
Then when it comes to affordable online
coaching, the main media for running that
business is just email marketing,
followed by some Instagram posts, but the
majority of that is email marketing.
When it comes to challenge time,
maybe 90%, 95% of all sales
are attributed to
that.
Which is going to bring me into our next
step, organic versus paid marketing.
For the majority of you out there,
you should master organic because it's
going to
cost you a lot of money to get millions of
people to see your reel or your YouTube
video. But if you can get good at organic,
you can get it done for free.
But either way,
you're going to have to pay for people's
attention.
You're either going to have to pay in
time, energy,
and effort by getting better at
the trade of making good content,
or you're going to have to pay whichever
social
media platform it is to put it in front of
them.
The biggest charlatans online will tell
you not to worry about
organic and instead just to focus on paid.
The reason is that it's very difficult
and it's very time-consuming,
and it's very
energy and resource-draining to get good
organic content. But think about this.
The better you get at organic content
and making reels and YouTube videos,
whatever it is,
you're also generating the same skills to
understand what's going
to resonate with paid. In my opinion,
if you cannot master organic content, do
not go to paid yet. Paid is the icing
that goes on top of the cake.
But if you cannot bake the cake yet,
do not get distracted with icing.
Organic, you pay with time, energy,
and effort. Paid, you pay with money.
In marketing as well,
we have direct marketing
and we have awareness.
So direct marketing would be emails going
out to people.
Black Friday, join my offer,
discount going now, buy today.
Nutonic bundle offer,
two months of productivity to your door
for £100, whatever
it is. It's direct marketing.
But then on the other end of the spectrum,
we have
awareness.
So right now there's going to be some
overlaid footage of my car getting
wrapped in Nutonic.
The second I drive out of
that shop with that on, we don't get
people buying Nutonic.
Then the footage here you'll see
is the time that we went
to Las Vegas and sponsored a jujitsu
tournament and gave someone $50,000 US
for the submission of the night. Again,
giving out loads of cans of Nutonic in
Vegas,
we didn't see a massive uptick in sales
that month or that
day. So sometimes
when it comes to marketing, there
are things you can do today to
get sales, but there
are also other things you can do
that won't uptick your sales
at all but can build your awareness.
The biggest mistake
that I find people make
is sometimes they put some eggs into
the basket of building awareness for their
brand and their business, and they
expect to make money from it. Even
when we look at social media platforms,
TikTok
to me is mostly just an awareness
platform.
Sure, some people run good businesses
and TikTok shop does well.
But for the time being,
because I haven't really got
that many funnels set up on
TikTok, I just use it to build awareness.
So make sure that
when you're spending money
and you're doing energy and effort in
your marketing, some stuff
is going to bring you sales,
other stuff is going to
build up your brand so that people
are going to know it,
maybe ask questions about
it,
or maybe just be nurtured far enough down
the process until they buy.
Another thing we need to think about in
marketing is search marketing versus
discovery marketing.
The biggest mistake people make
when they go to YouTube is
they think that people
are searching for their video,
but they're not.
Maybe if your video
is about how to change the settings on
your
FX3 camera, people
are going to search for that.
But the majority of content on YouTube
is now browsed for.
Some people spend a lot of money with
things like SEO, which stands for search
engine optimization. But in my opinion,
those days are dying.
I think that even search engines as we
know them, like Google, are going to be
replaced by AI and ChatGPT very soon.
The future of marketing
is what I call discovery-based marketing.
I looked at the analytics on my YouTube
before making this video.
12.7 times more views come from people
discovering
my videos than searching for them.
It's why titles, thumbnails,
and packaging is so important.
So if we rule search out of the equation
and we're going to get discovered, the two
biggest things we need from this,
good packaging, titles and thumbnails.
The other thing is good hooks. Because
if you're using a social media platform
like
TikTok, like Instagram Reels,
like YouTube Shorts,
instead of people seeing your
packaging, they're going to see your hook.
And here's a rule
that I want all of you to work with.
Watch back a piece of content
when you create it.
And if in the first eight seconds you
don't know what it's about, what problem
it solves, and what they're going to get,
you need to reformulate the hook.
You have about eight seconds.
If they do not know what they're going to
get in that
time, they're going to go.
The next differentiation we need to make
in marketing is
products versus services. Here
is a golden rule for any of you that
are going to
get into this realm.
You can discount a product
but never a service.
Because if you discount a product,
you just make less margin.
If you discount a service,
you end up with less time.
And time is just something
that you shouldn't be selling
or giving away for
anything less than it is already.
So products would be Nutonic
and affordable
online coaching. The reason
that I put that as a product
is the more people that
buy that, they don't get my time.
I end up paying the coaches,
and we just make
less profit. The mentorship
is a service because it's directly tied to
my time.
If youDouble the amount of people in my
mentorship, you sap a lot of time out of
me. You can discount products,
run promotions. Don't do that on services.
Most people start off in a service-based
industry, whether it's personal training,
being a physio, or whatever it is.
Then after a while,
they like to take whatever
it is they're doing
and put it into a product,
because products are easy to scale.
Services are not. And the last thing
that we need to look at that's very
important
when it comes to marketing,
business to business versus business to
customer or
consumer. The majority of gurus
that you follow online operate
business-to-business
businesses. The way you market these
are very different.
Business to business, your customers
are often going to get a return on
investment,
which means if they spend 1,000,
they should make 10,000 back.
My course, two and a half K.
I expect you to make
that back in a few months.
But if you use my training app
or you buy a new tonic,
there's no guarantee that
you're going to spend $100 with us
and get that back.
So a lot of the time,
you want to sell it for return on
investment in B2B.
In B2C, you want to sell the experience,
the solution, so more productivity
or workouts all taken care of.
You're probably going to work with smaller
margins
in B2C, and by nature,
you're probably going to end up doing more
organic
marketing. The reason being,
if you don't make massive margins on your
B2C, you've
got less money to play with paid ads,
which means you probably
are going to have to
turn up, put out more content,
do live streams, do live webinars,
do everything you
can to build that business.
Whereas a lot of people in the B2B space
have massive
margins to spend on paid ads,
and they can often hire big teams.
Typically B2B, fewer clients,
bigger deals.
And the biggest trap you need to avoid
is that a lot of the people
that you follow
in this realm that have their Ferraris
and Lamborghinis or whatever are
telling you what to do to build your
business when many of you are running the
B2C business.
My best advice would be become a weapon of
organic digital online content.
If you do that,
you don't need their shitty
advice.
So there's a comprehensive guide into
digital marketing. Pick your socials.
Post to all of them if you can.
The majority of you
are going to want to use some
form of email marketing because then you
can move into a passive sales system.
This is pretty much the formula
that I put out in every video.
Build your socials,
get people knowing you,
get people interested in your brand.
Choose some kind of value-based commodity
that you could give someone, like the
ones in the description.
Send people to a page where they can find
out everything
about your products and services
and sell to them.
All of those terminologies
that you may not have understood before
should be made
clear from this video.
If you made it this far to the end,
make sure to check out
the links in the description.